HI. IT'S ME, WHYATT.
READY TO GO ON
A READING ADVENTURE?
SUPER!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
IT'S "KING MIDAS"!
IN THIS STORY, WE'LL
USE THE ALPHABET...
PRACTISE THE MAGIC
OF SPELLING...
AND USE THE POWER TO READ
TO CHANGE THE STORY.
LET'S GO!
"SUPER WHY" IS FUNDED BY:
♪♪ WHO ANSWERS THE CALL
FOR FRIENDS IN NEED? ♪♪
♪♪ SUPER WHY ♪♪
♪♪ HE'S THE GUY
HE'S SUPER WHY ♪♪
♪♪ WHO'S GOT THE POWER
THE POWER TO READ? ♪♪
♪♪ WHO LOOKS INTO BOOKS
FOR THE ANSWERS WE NEED? ♪♪
♪♪ SUPER WHY ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE SUPER READERS
WE'RE GONNA FLY ♪♪
♪♪ COME ALONG ♪♪
♪♪ WITH THE SUPER READERS ♪♪
♪♪ ADVENTURE WAITS WHEN
YOU'RE WITH SUPER WHY ♪♪
♪♪ SUPER WHY AND
THE SUPER READERS ♪♪
♪♪ YEAH ♪♪
♪♪ SUPER WHY AND
THE SUPER READERS ♪♪
♪♪ ADVENTURE WAITS WHEN
YOU'RE WITH SUPER WHY ♪♪
♪♪ YEAH! SUPER WHY ♪♪
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
HI! SO GLAD
YOU'RE HERE.
IT'S ME, WHYATT!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
WELCOME TO
STORYBROOK VILLAGE,
WHERE ALL OUR
FAIRY-TALE FRIENDS LIVE!
[ Cellphone ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
OH LOOK!
PIG'S PLAYING
WITH A TOY CAR.
COOL!
LET'S GO CHECK IT OUT!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
COME ON!
VROOM, VROOM!
ZOOM!
[ Imitating brakes ]
HI, PIG!
OH HI, WHYATT!
LOOK AT
MY COOL CAR!
VROOM-VROOM!
OH, I LOVE IT!
÷÷ME, TOO!
WATCH IT
GO REALLY,
REALLY FAST.
VROOM, VROOM!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
WHOA!
HEY, WHYATT, YOU
KNOW WHAT WOULD
BE EVEN MORE FUN
THAN ONE TOY CAR?
WHAT?
MORE TOY CARS!
THEN I COULD
RACE ALL OF THEM!
YEAH, THAT
WOULD BE FUN.
YEAH! BUT...
I ONLY HAVE
THIS ONE CAR.
I WANT MORE CARS!
THIS SOUNDS LIKE
A SUPER BIG PROBLEM.
AND A SUPER BIG
PROBLEM NEEDS US...
THE SUPER READERS!
WE NEED TO CALL THE REST
OF THE SUPER READERS.
CALL THEM WITH ME!
[ Cellphone ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
SAY, "CALLING ALL
SUPER READERS!"
Children: [ In audience ]
CALLING ALL
SUPER READERS!
[ Remote phone ringing ]
TO THE BOOK CLUB!
Children:
COME ON,
TO THE BOOK CLUB!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
WHYATT HERE.
"P" IS FOR PIG!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
RED RIDING HOOD
ROLLIN' IN!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
PRINCESS PEA
AT YOUR SERVICE!
AND YOU,
SAY YOUR NAME.
GREAT. WE'RE
ALL HERE.
TOGETHER, WE WILL
SOLVE PIG'S PROBLEM!
LET'S GO!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
[ Electronic beeps ]
OKAY, PIG...
STATE YOUR
PROBLEM.
I HAVE ONE
REALLY FUN TOY CAR,
BUT I WANT MORE.
MORE CARS?
WHAT DO I
DO IF I WANT
MORE TOY CARS?
GOOD QUESTION.
WHEN WE HAVE A QUESTION,
WE LOOK...
All:
IN A BOOK!
WHICH BOOK
SHOULD WE LOOK IN?
PEAS AND CARROTS,
CARROTS AND PEAS.
BOOK COME OUT,
PLEASE, PLEASE, PLEASE!
LET'S READ THE TITLE
OF THIS BOOK.
WE KNOW WHAT TO DO.
WE NEED TO JUMP
INTO THIS BOOK...
AND FIND THE ANSWER
TO PIG'S QUESTION.
FIRST, WE LOOK
FOR SUPER LETTERS.
AND THEN, PUT THEM IN...
OUR SUPER DUPER...
COMPUTER!
SUPER DUPER COMPUTER,
HOW MANY SUPER LETTERS
DO WE NEED?
[ Beeping ]
OH! IN THIS STORY,
WE NEED EIGHT
SUPER LETTERS!
AND THEN WE'LL GET...
[ Triumphant ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
OUR SUPER STORY ANSWER!
IT'S TIME TO TRANSFORM.
READY?
All:
READY!
ARMS IN!
PUT YOUR ARM IN.
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
Whyatt:
SUPER READERS...
All:
TO THE RESCUE!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
ALPHA PIG!
WITH ALPHABET POWER!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
WONDER RED!
WITH WORD POWER!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
PRINCESS PRESTO
WITH SPELLING POWER!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
SUPER WHY,
WITH THE POWER TO READ!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
AND SUPER YOU
WITH THE POWER
TO HELP!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
TOGETHER,
WE ARE...
All:
THE SUPER READERS!
WHY-FLYERS!
WE'RE READY TO FLY
INTO THIS BOOK!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
♪♪ SUPER READERS ♪♪
♪♪TO THE RESCUE!♪♪
♪♪ IT'S TIME TO FLY
WITH THE SUPER READERS ♪♪
♪♪ 'CAUSE WE'VE GOT
A PROBLEM TO SOLVE ♪♪
♪♪ SUPER READERS ♪♪
♪♪TO THE RESCUE!♪♪
♪♪ WORKING TOGETHER
WITH POWERS TO READ ♪♪
♪♪ INTO BOOKS WE FLY ♪♪
♪♪ TO FIND
THE SUPER STORY ANSWER ♪♪
♪♪ WITH SUPER WHY ♪♪
♪♪ SUPER READERS
TO THE RESCUE! ♪♪
PRESTO!
OH!
WE'RE IN THE
"KING MIDAS" BOOK!
LET'S READ.
WHY WRITER...
HIGHLIGHT!
READ WITH ME.
I LOVE GOLD!
AND I LIKE IT!
[ Smack ]
I WANT MORE GOLD!
YES! YEAH!
[ Gasp ]
KING MIDAS WANTS MORE GOLD,
JUST LIKE I WANT
MORE TOY CARS!
AND THAT,
SUPER READERS,
IS WHY WE ARE
IN THIS BOOK.
PIG AND KING MIDAS
BOTH WANT MORE.
TO KING MIDAS!
LET'S ROLL!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
HI! WE'RE THE
SUPER READERS.
I AM KING MIDAS,
AND I LOVE GOLD!
LOTS AND LOTS OF GOLD!
AHEM...
IN FACT, I WISH
THAT EVERYTHING I
TOUCH WITH THIS FINGER
TURNS TO GOLD!
[ Fanfare ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
OLD VASE,
GOLD VASE?
Various:
WOW! AWESOME!
WHOA!
IT WORKED!
NOW, THANKS TO MY
SPECIAL GOLDEN FINGER,
EVERYTHING I TOUCH
WILL TURN TO GOLD,
AND I'LL HAVE
LOTS MORE GOLD.
LIKE UM...
OOH, THE PATH,
THE PATH, THE PATH.
OLD PATH,
GOLD PATH!
Super Readers:
WHOA!
[ Cackle ]
LOOK AT ME!
I'M WALKING
ON GOLD!
[ Giggle ]
AND I LIKE IT!
WHEE! MORE GOLD!
OLD TREE, GOLD TREE!
YES! HAH-HAH!
I'M GOLD-HAPPY!
AND I LIKE IT!
WHEW.
ALL OF THIS TURNING
THINGS TO GOLD
HAS MADE ME THIRSTY.
I'D LIKE A BIG,
TALL GLASS OF MILK.
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
AH, YES.
BUT DO YOU KNOW WHAT
WOULD BE EVEN BETTER?
[ Giggle ]
OLD MILK, GOLD MILK!
BOTTOMS UP!
[ Clunking ]
UH, INTERESTING.
GOLD MILK
IS VERY...
UH... HARD.
OH, WHAT CAN I DO?
ALPHA PIG TO THE RESCUE!
WITH MY AMAZING
ALPHABET TOOLS,
I CAN FIND THE LETTERS
IN THE WORD "MILK"
AND CHANGE THE GOLD
BACK INTO MILK!
A-B-C, SING WITH ME!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
♪♪ SING WITH ME ♪♪
AMAZING
ALPHABET SINGING!
HMM...
NOW WHERE'S
THE LETTER
"M"?
Children:
THERE!
Alpha Pig:
THERE'S
THE "M"!
[ Sloshing ]
NOW WE NEED
THE LETTER "I".
WHERE'S÷÷THE "I"?
Children:
THERE!
Alpha Pig:
THERE'S
THE "I"!
NEXT WE NEED
THE LETTER "L".
WHERE'S÷÷THE "L"?
Children:
THERE!
Alpha Pig:
THERE'S
THE "L"!
[ Gasp ]
ONLY ONE MORE
LETTER TO GO!
NOW WHERE
IS THE "K"?
÷÷HMM.
Children:
THERE
IT IS!
Alpha Pig:
THERE'S
THE "K"!
÷÷WHOA!
LICKETY LETTERS!
WE TURNED THE GOLD
BACK INTO MILK!
LET'S GIVE OURSELVES
A BIG THUMBS UP!
BE SURE TO KEEP
YOUR EYES OUT
FOR SUPER LETTERS!
THANKS,
SUPER READERS!
NO PROBLEM.
[ Slurping ]
AH, SO NICE.
NOW I'M READY TO
MAKE MORE GOLD!
Wonder Red:
THERE HE GOES!
[ Whooping ]
GOLD!
÷÷GOLD!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
YOU SEE SUPER LETTERS?
WHICH LETTERS
DID YOU FIND?
Children:
"H"! "N"!
"H", "N". OH YEAH!
LET'S PUT THEM IN
OUR SUPER DUPER...
COMPUTER!
SIX MORE SUPER LETTERS
AND THEN WE'LL GET
OUR SUPER STORY ANSWER!
SUPER DUPER!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
OLD STATUE,
GOLD STATUE!
KING MIDAS,
DON'T YOU THINK
YOU MIGHT HAVE
ENOUGH GOLD?
YOU DO HAVE
A LOT OF GOLD.
BUT I WANT MORE GOLD!
MORE!
AFTER ALL, I LIKE IT!
OOH! VISITORS!
[ Grunts ]
Both:
HI, MIDAS!
WE HEARD YOU'VE GOT
THE "GOLDEN TOUCH"!
I SURE DO!
COME TO MY
FISHY FOUNTAIN
AND I'LL
SHOW YOU!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
THIS IS MY
FISHY FOUNTAIN!
Both:
OOH, AAH...
GET A LOAD
OF THIS.
OLD FOUNTAIN...
GOLD FOUNTAIN!
Both:
OOH, SHINY.
LET'S SWIM!
Both:
WHEE! WAHOO!
WHAT FUN!
[ Laughter ]
OH, I JUST LOVE SWIMMING
IN MY FISHY FOUNTAIN!
HEY...
YOU KNOW WHAT'S
EVEN BETTER
THAN A GOLD
FISHY FOUNTAIN?
OLD WATER...
WAIT FOR IT.
GOLD WATER!
OH, MY CHINNY-
CHIN-CHIN!
[ Grunts ]
Both:
MIDAS, WE CAN'T...
[ Straining ]
MOVE!
[ Grunting ]
UH-OH. I... I
CAN'T MOVE AT ALL!
I'VE TURNED
THE WATER INTO GOLD
AND NOW WE'RE TRAPPED!
I DON'T LIKE IT!
WHAT CAN I DO?
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
CUE THE SPARKLES!
CUE THE MUSIC!
PRINCESS PRESTO
TO THE RESCUE!
WITH MY MAGIC
SPELLING WAND,
I CAN SPELL
THE WORD "WATER"
AND TURN THE GOLD
BACK TO WATER.
TAKE OUT YOUR MAGIC
SPELLING WANDS!
READY?
WANDS UP!
SPELL WITH ME!
HMM.
WHAT MAKES
THE SOUND "WUH"?
Children:
"W"!
"W"! WRITE
A "W" WITH ME!
NOW, WE NEED AN "A"!
WRITE AN "A" WITH ME.
[ Gasp ]
IT'S WORKING!
LET'S KEEP GOING!
WHAT LETTER MAKES
THE SOUND "TUH-TUH-TUH"?
Children:
"T"!
"T"! LET'S WRITE A "T"!
GREAT!
TWO MORE LETTERS TO GO.
THE "E" AND THE "R"
MAKE THE "ERR"
SOUND IN "WATER".
WRITE AN "E" WITH ME.
NOW WRITE
THE "R" WITH ME.
PRESTO!
÷÷HOORAY!
[ Giggles ]
[ Gasp ]
SPECTACULAR
SPELLING!
WE SPELLED
"WATER"
AND TURNED THE GOLD
BACK TO WATER.
LET'S TAKE A BOW.
I HAVE
MY WATER BACK.
NOW WE CAN
SWIM AGAIN!
Both:÷÷OH, NO.
YOU MIGHT TURN IT
BACK INTO GOLD!
WELL, I DO
LIKE GOLD...
SAY, WHO'S HUNGRY?
UH, LET'S GO
GET SOME FOOD!
Both:
YUM! WE'RE
STARVING!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
WE'D BETTER
FOLLOW MIDAS.
COME ON!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
YOU SEE MORE
SUPER LETTERS?
WHICH LETTERS?
Children:
"A"! "L"! "U"!
OH, YEAH! "A", "L", "U".
NOW WE NEED TO PUT THEM
IN OUR SUPER DUPER...
COMPUTER!
THREE MORE
SUPER LETTERS,
AND THEN WE'LL GET
OUR SUPER STORY ANSWER!
RIGHT ON, READERS!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
AH, DINNER
WITH FRIENDS.
BUT, UH...
YOU KNOW WHAT
WOULD BE BETTER
THAN THIS FOOD?
[ Giggle ]
Super Readers:
UH-OH.
GOLD FOOD!
[ Cackle ]
OLD SOUP,
GOLD SOUP!
[ Clang ]÷÷OH!
OLD TURKEY,
GOLD TURKEY!
[ Clunk ]÷÷OUCH!
SO, FRIENDS,
DO YOU LIKE
MY GOLD FOOD?
Friends:
NO, WE DON'T!
WE CAN'T EAT FOOD
THAT'S MADE OF GOLD!
F-FRIENDS, WAIT!
WE HAVEN'T
EVEN FINISHED
OUR GOLD DINNER!
Friends:÷÷GOODBYE!
OH, DON'T GO!
OLD FRIENDS,
GOLD FRIENDS!
UH, HELLO?
GOLD FRIEND?
HOO, HAH!
HIGH-FIVES?
OH NO!
I CAN'T TALK AND PLAY
WITH MY GOLD FRIENDS.
MAYBE I'LL JUST
HAVE A LITTLE SNACK.
[ Clunk ]
AH!
I CAN'T EAT
MY GOLD FOOD!
I DON'T WANT
ALL THIS GOLD.
BUT ALAS,
IT IS MY STORY.
BUT IT'S NOT TRUE.
WHAT CAN I DO?
SUPER WHY TO THE RESCUE!
WITH THE POWER TO READ,
I CAN CHANGE THIS STORY
AND SAVE THE DAY!
LET'S CHANGE
THE WORD "MORE"
IN THIS SENTENCE.
Z-ZAP!
WHY WRITER, WRITE!
SUPER READERS, WHAT IS
THE OPPOSITE OF "MORE"?
LET'S TRY "LESS".
WHERE'S THE WORD "LESS"?
IT STARTS WITH AN "L".
Children:
THERE!
Z-ZAP!
LET'S READ IT AND
SEE WHAT HAPPENS.
Friends:÷÷MIDAS!
[ Gasp ]
FRIENDS!
FOOD!
NOW I HAVE LESS GOLD,
AND I LIKE IT!
[ Laugh ]
DID LESS GOLD
HELP KING MIDAS?
Children:
YES!
YES! SUPER JOB,
SUPER READERS.
WE CHANGED THE STORY
AND KING MIDAS
HAS LESS GOLD!
NOW I CAN ENJOY
EVERYTHING
THE WAY I
DID BEFORE.
YES INDEED,
I AM THANKFUL
FOR MY ONE
PIECE OF GOLD.
IT'S SPECIAL.
AND I LIKE IT!
[ Cheers ]
NOW...
LET'S EAT!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
YOU SEE SUPER LETTERS?
WHICH ONES?
Children:
"T"! "K"! "F"!
"T", "K" AND "F"?
OH YEAH!
LET'S PUT THEM IN
OUR SUPER DUPER...
COMPUTER!
WE FOUND ALL OF
OUR SUPER LETTERS.
NOW WE CAN GET
OUR SUPER STORY ANSWER!
Midas & friends:
GOODBYE,
SUPER READERS.
Super Readers:
GOODBYE, KING MIDAS!
GOODBYE, FRIENDS!
COME BACK
ANY TIME!
I'D LIKE THAT!
WHY-FLYERS,
BACK TO
THE BOOK CLUB!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
♪♪ WE FOUND THE
SUPER STORY ANSWER ♪♪
♪♪ WITH SUPER WHY ♪♪
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
[ Electronic beeps ]
SUPER DUPER COMPUTER,
GIVE US OUR
SUPER STORY ANSWER!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
READ WITH ME.
THE SUPER STORY
ANSWER IS...
[ Triumphant ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
BUT... WHY?
Red:
BECAUSE KING MIDAS
REALIZED HE DIDN'T NEED
A WHOLE KINGDOM OF GOLD
TO BE HAPPY.
HE WAS THANKFUL
FOR HIS ONE SPECIAL
PIECE OF GOLD.
SO MY
QUESTION IS:
WHAT SHOULD
I DO IF I WANT
MORE TOY CARS?
AND THE
ANSWER IS...
All:
THANKFUL!
OH!
I SHOULD BE THANKFUL
FOR MY ONE TOY CAR.
I REALLY SHOULD.
COME ON, LET'S GO!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
HEY! WATCH
MY CAR DO THIS!
VROOM, VROOM!
AWESOME,
LOOK AT IT GO!
OH, LOOK AT THAT!
[ Giggling ]
I GUESS ONE CAR CAN
STILL BE PRETTY FUN.
YOU REALLY DON'T
WANT MORE, HUH?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I DON'T!
I'M THANKFUL
FOR THE ONE
TOY CAR I HAVE.
'CAUSE IT'S
SPECIAL.
HIP, HIP, HOORAY!
THE SUPER READERS
SAVE THE DAY!
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
♪♪ HIP, HIP, HOORAY ♪♪
♪♪HOORAY!♪♪
♪♪ THE SUPER READERS
SAVE THE DAY ♪♪
♪♪ WE CHANGED THE STORY ♪♪
♪♪ WE SOLVED
THE PROBLEM ♪♪
♪♪ WE WORKED TOGETHER
SO HIP, HIP, HOORAY! ♪♪
♪♪ HIP, HIP, HOORAY ♪♪
♪♪HOORAY!♪♪
♪♪ THE SUPER READERS
SAVE THE DAY ♪♪
♪♪ HIP, HIP, HOORAY ♪♪
♪♪HOORAY!♪♪
♪♪ THE SUPER READERS
SAVE THE DAY! ♪♪
[ ♪♪♪♪♪♪ ]
♪♪ I LOVE TO SPELL ♪♪
♪♪ I REALLY
LOVE TO SPELL ♪♪
♪♪I REALLY
LOVE TO SPELL♪♪
♪♪ WHAT LETTER MAKES
A "BUH" SOUND? ♪♪
AN "EH" SOUND? ♪♪
♪♪ WHAT LETTER
MAKES A "LUH" SOUND? ♪♪
♪♪ WHAT LETTER MAKES
A "LUH" SOUND? ♪♪
THAT'S "L"!
♪♪ PUT IT ALL TOGETHER
AND WHAT DOES IT SPELL? ♪♪
[ Chimes ]
♪♪ BELL ♪♪
♪♪ I LOVE TO SPELL ♪♪
♪♪ I REALLY
LOVE TO SPELL ♪♪
♪♪I REALLY LOVE
TO SPELL♪♪
♪♪ I LOVE TO SPELL ♪♪
♪♪ I REALLY
LOVE TO SPELL ♪♪
♪♪ THERE'S PRINCESS PEA ♪♪
"SUPER WHY" IS FUNDED BY: